A Guide to the Robinson Family Papers, 1684-1915
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
- Family history papers: records, wills, lawsuits, Herald's College correspondence, etc. (Volume I)
  - Copy of a letter from Christopher Robinson, Oriel College, to Catherine Robinson (mother), Virginia(?), 3 December 1725.
    Concerns Christopher's health and candles sent from Catherine by the last ship.
  - Notes on sources. (Page 652-671)
    Extracts from records found in England and Virginia concerning Christopher Robinson and Bishop Robinson's descendants, particularly Clara Robinson, Sir Edward Wood, John Robinson of Cleasby, Thomas Robinson, and Theophilus Bolton. Includes copies of royal petitions and patents.
  - H.W. Forsyth Harwood, Kensington, to C.W. Robinson, 30 October 1913. (Page 673-674)
    Concerns the diary of Alexander Bennett.
  - Journal excerpt. (Page 675-696)
    Diary and genealogy of Alexander Bennett published in The Genealogist, Volume XX, January and April 1904.
  - Copy of a letter from Henry Wood to "His Excellency," 15 July 1712. (Page 696a)
    Relates personal news.
  - Photographs. (Page 697)
    Four black and white photos of unidentified churches and churchyards.
  - Copy of a diary, 1855. (Page 697a-708)
    Portion of 1855 diary entries by C.W. Robinson's father including information on visits to Frenchay and Cleasby.
  - Copy of a portrait. (Page unnumbered)
    Unidentified man painted by Beverley Robinson and given to Charles Walker (C.W. Robinson's grandfather).
  - Notes on sources. (Page 709-743)
    Extracts and explanations of sources tracing the pedigree of C.W. Robinson's mother's family, the Walkers, Merrys, Lukins, and Booths. Includes portions of letters, marriage certificates, and a map of London.
  - Notes on sources, March 1914. (Page 746)
    Further documentation described by C.W. Robinson concerning his Pedigree application to Herald's College.
  - H.F. Burke, Heralds College, London, to C.W. Robinson, Ealing, 12 February 1914. (Page 748)
    Concerns a scheduled meeting.
  - Copy of letter excerpt from C.W. Robinson to H.F. Burke, 3 March 1914. (Page 749-752)
    Concerns family pedigree research about Bishop Robinson and relatives from Cleasby.
  - Memorandum, 1875. (Page 753-764)
    Concerns pedigree research about members of the Robinson family living from the late 1500s to the early 1600s.
  - H.F. Burke, Herald's College, London, to C.W. Robinson, Ealing, 20 March 1914. (Page 764a)
    Concerns receipt of documents.
  - H.F. Burke, Herald's College, London, to C.W. Robinson, Ealing, 26 March 1914. (Page 765)
    Concerns outstanding debt owed for research.
  - H.F. Burke, Herald's College, London, to C.W. Robinson, Ealing, 28 March 1914. (Page 766)
    Concerns the letter of 26 March.
  - H.F. Burke, Herald's College, London, to C.W. Robinson, Ealing, 4 November 1914. (Page 767)
    Concerns pedigree research.
  - H.F. Burke, Herald's College, London, to C.W. Robinson, Ealing, 13 May 1915.
  - Note, 19 May 1915. (Page 768)
    Explanation of pedigree research information obtained from H.F. Burke during May 1915.
  - Note, 28 January 1916. (Page 769)
    Explanation of pedigree research information obtained from H.F. Burke during January 1916.
  - C.S. MacInnes, Toronto, to C.W. Robinson, Ealing, 31 March 1915. (Page unnumbered)
    Concerns a portrait of Peter Robinson with newspaper article from The Peterborough Daily about Peter Robinson's public life.
  - Letters, 1910-1913. (Page unnumbered)
    Miscellaneous correspondences from Herald's College, London to C.W. Robinson listing fees owed for the research and registry of Robinson family pedigree.
- Original Family Papers: Virginia and Canada, 1684-1798.
  - Introduction. (Page 1)
    C.W. Robinson's explanation of the book's contents of original family papers from the "Hewick" Robinsons and how he came to possess them.
  - Papers Concerning Christopher Robinson III of Hewick.
    - Memorandum, 1880. (Page 3-6)
      Further explanation of family papers contained within, how the Robinsons established themselves as landholders in Virginia, Robinson family participation in the American Revolution. Includes one color and one black and white sketch of Hewick, Virginia.
    - Map. (Page 8)
      Map of Virginia, Pennsylvania. Delaware, New Jersey, and Maryland showing Robinson Creek and area near Urbanna, Virginia where "Hewick" stood (Middlesex County).
    - Pedigree. (Page 12-13)
      Rough sketch of Robinson family of Virginia as descended from Christopher Robinson, first immigrant to America.
    - Index. (Page 7-27)
      Listing of contents as compiled by C.W. Robinson.
    - Will of Christopher Robinson I, c. 1700. (Page 34)
      Portion of the will of Christopher Robinson I, written by Edmund Pendleton.
    - Map, 2 December 1684. (Page 37)
      Shows the 660 acres of land owned by Christopher Wormeley in James City County showing roads and waterways.
    - Account, 1727-1731 (Page 41)
      Money paid to and from Hewick, England, by Christopher Robinson.
    - General Robert Porteus, Yorkshire, England, to Christopher Robinson, Rappahannock River, Virginia, 26 November 1750. (Page 43)
      Business accounts and transactions enacted by Porteus as Robinson's agent at Hewick, England.
    - Will of Christopher Robinson III of Hewick, 6 December 1751. (Page 47-49)
      Wills estate in England to brother John Robinson, estate in Virginia (Hewick) to daughter Judith Robinson, estate in Virginia (Grange) to daughter Mary.
    - John Maynard, London, to Christopher Robinson III, 20 April 1762. (Page 55)
      Concerns the Yorkshire estate, shipping tobacco from America. Includes copy of letter from John Maynard to Captain Brookes.
    - Account, 1764-1765. (Page 59)
      Concerns duties, freight and shipping costs on tobacco rendered to Christopher Robinson III.
    - Account, 1765-1766. (Page 63)
      Concerns rents owed and paid by tenants on Hewick, England, to Christopher Robinson III.
    - Receipt, July 1770. (Page 63)
      Quarterly Royal Land Tax paid by Hewick, England, 5p 6s 1d.
    - Graham Frank(?) to Christopher Robinson(?), 13 February 1765. (Page 65-68)
      Concerns a theft attempt at Hewick, England, other Hewick business.
    - Graham Frank to Christopher Robinson(?) (Page 71-78)
      Concerns the house at Bedford, England, proposed sale of property. Mentions Bishop Robinson. Letter is mutilated.
    - Graham Frank(?), London, to Christopher Robinson(?), 23 July 1765. (Page 81-84)
      Concerns purchase of Parker lands, management of Hewick, England.
    - Graham Frank to Christopher Robinson, near Urbanna in Middlesex County, Virginia, c. 1760. (Page 86-89)
      Concerns Robinson's estates in London, arranging to bring water to the fields from the river, tenants' grievances, general upkeep of fences and barns.
    - Graham Frank, London, to Christopher Robinson, near Urbanna in Middlesex County, Virginia, 2 May 1776. (Page 90-96)
      Concerns Hewick, England, planting oak trees, tenants and rent collection, general upkeep, fence dividing Robinson's and Lord Devonshire's lands, Virginia stock holdings.
    - Graham Frank(?), London, to Christopher Robinson(?), Virginia, 20 December 1766. (Page 99-115)
      Concerns quarrels with tenants over upkeep of Hewick, England and disputes over hunting rights with neighboring landowners
    - Graham Frank and (?)Bickerton, London, to Christopher Robinson, Virginia, 21 December 1767. (Page 117-118)
      Concerns the sale of Hewick, England with estimated value of 16,000 pounds.
    - Petition. (Page 121)
      Concerns Richard Corbin and Ralph Wormeley, executors of Christopher Robinson III's (deceased) holdings in Virginia.
    - Robert Cary and Co., London, to Richard Corbin and Ralph Wormeley, Virginia, 24 May 1770. (Page 122-125)
      Concerns the execution of Christopher Robinson's will. Fletcher Norton, speaker for the House of Commons possible purchaser of Hewick, England.
    - Robert Cary and Co., London, to Richard Corbin and Ralph Wormeley, Virginia, 4 March 1772. (Page 126-129)
      Concerns the sale of Hewick, England to Speaker of the House of Commons, Fletcher Norton, by Act of Parliament.
    - Robert Cary and Co., London, to Richard Corbin and Ralph Wormeley, York River, Virginia, 24 August 1772. (Page 130-133)
      Concerns the sale of Hewick, England to Fletcher Norton, Speaker of the House of Commons, for 16,000 pounds.
    - Account, 1722. (Page 134-137)
      Concerns expenses incurred in passing 9 June 1772 Act of Parliament for the sale of Christopher Robinson's Hewick, England.
    - Christopher Robinson to Richard Corbin, 4 August 1767. (Page 138)
      Concerns money owed Christopher Robinson for the estate of Peter Robinson.
    - Receipt, 21 June 1769. (Page 138)
      Signed by P.W. Claiborne for money paid by David Ker on behalf of Christopher Robinson for the education of Peter Robinson's son.
    - Account, 1767-1768. (Page 142)
      Concerns money owed by Christopher Robinson to John Craine for tailoring services rendered.
    - Account, 1768. (Page 144)
      Concerns money owed by Christopher Robinson to James Mills for medical services rendered.
    - Account, 1769. (Page 146)
      Concerns the purchase of slaves and stock by Richard Corbin and Ralph Wormeley as acting guardians of Christopher Robinson IV.
    - Edmund Pendleton, Edmundsburg, to Richard Corbin, Laneville, King and Queen County, Virginia, 15 July 1786. (Page 148)
      Concerns money owed to the estate of Christopher Robinson.
  - Papers concerning Christopher Robinson of the Queen's Rangers (Loyalist Hussars)
    - Account, 1740-1749. (Page 168)
      Concerns money owed by Peter Robinson (d. 1765) to John Robinson (d. 1787).
    - Account book, 1777. (Page 170)
      Monthly record of financial exchanges recorded by John Robinson of Middlesex County, Virginia.
    - Accounts (fragments), 1775-1777. (Page 172)
      Eight receipts of notes of purchases made by John Robinson of Middlesex County, Virginia including one receipt for the hire of two slaves (1777).
    - Letter from David Ker, 22 June 1765. (Page 174)
      Concerns payments owed to an unidentified account. Mentions "Mr. Dinwiddie".
    - Receipt, 26 September 1765. (Page 178)
      Concerns payment for wine purchased by Beverley Robinson.
    - Royal warrant, 18 February 1780. (Page 182)
      Authorization for John Dessen to raise two battalions of soldiers for England's Regular Troops to be used for the duration of the American Revolution. Signed by Robert Rogers.
    - Royal commission, 26 June 1781. (Page 184)
      Naming Christopher Robinson IV to the post of Captain of the Queen's Rangers in New York under Lieutenant Colonel John Graves Simcoe.
    - Beverley Robinson, Northlake(?), to "My Dear Daughter," 3 July 1784. (Page 190-194)
      Concerns family matters, sending tea, mentions grandchildren.
    - Royal commission, 1 June 1792. (Page 197-200)
      Appoints Christopher Robinson IV to the post of "Inspector of the Woods, Reserves, and all Rents and Profits of the Crown" in Upper Canada. Signed by John Graves Simcoe.
    - Petition, 17 October 1792. (Page 203-206)
      Transferring power of attorney from Peter Russell to Christopher Robinson IV for the power to lease and/or collect rents on certain properties on the River Cabaraqui, Upper Canada.
    - Petition, 4 April 1793. (Page 209-210)
      John Wentworth, Surveyor General of the Woods, Nova Scotia naming Christopher Robinson IV as his deputy in Upper Canada.
    - Christopher Robinson IV, Kensington, Upper Canada, to Robert Robinson, Digby, Nova Scotia, 6 July 1793. (Page 213-216)
      Concerns Christopher's post as deputy of the Woods.
    - Account, 1792-1798. (Page 219)
      Fees owed by Christopher Robinson IV for the education of his sons.
    - Peter Russell, Niagara, to Christopher Robinson IV, Kingston, Upper Canada, 1 November 1792. (Page 223)
      Concerns the sale of Cabaraqui mills.
    - D.W. Smith, Survey General's Office, Niagara, to Christopher Robinson IV(?), 21 April 1790. (Page 225)
      Concerns Smith's public account.
    - Peter Russell, Niagara, to Christopher Robinson IV, Upper Canada, 26 April 1794. (Page 229-232)
      Concerns mills being built along the Cabaraqui River, possibility that the seat of government will move to York (Toronto).
    - Royal commission, 22 July 1794. (Page 235)
      Appoints Christopher Robinson IV, Kingston, Upper Canada to the position of Royal Attorney and Advocate. Signed by William Mayne and initialed by John Graves Simcoe.
    - William Mayne to Christopher Robinson IV, Kingston Upper Canada, 26 July 1794. (Page 241)
      Concerns license to practice law in the Royal Courts.
    - Christopher Robinson IV to Governor John Graves Simcoe, 5 November 1795. (Page 245-248)
      Concerns Robinson's apprehension about his 4 April 1793 commission by John Wentworth.
    - Peter Russell, Newark, to Christopher Robinson IV, 26 May 1793. (Page 249)
      Concerns Robinson's "indisposition."
    - Peter Russell to Christopher Robinson IV, 28 February 1795. (Page 249)
      Concerns Robinson's recovery from illness.
    - Indenture, 29 August 1796. (Page 253)
      Appoints Christopher Robinson IV as Representative of the residents of Addington and Ontario Counties.
    - Deed, 22 July 1797. (Page 257-260)
      Concerns the Sale of land in Murray Township, Upper Canada owned by Christopher Robinson IV to Thomas Spencer of Canadague, New York.
    - Court notes, 26 April 1797. (Page 261-264)
      John Ferguson v. David Palmer over 100 pound debt.
    - Contract, 3 May 1798. (Page 267-268)
      Between Christopher Robinson IV, Kingston and Jacob Shepherd Clay, Herkermer County making Clay a six month laborer paid in money and/or land upon the end of service.
    - Contract, 3 May 1798. (Page 271-272)
      Between Christopher Robinson IV, Kingston and John Smith, Albana County, New York making Smith a six month laborer paid in money and/or land upon the end of service.
    - Contract, 24 July 1798. (Page 275-278)
      Between Christopher Robinson and John Woodward and David Bennet engaging Woodward and Bennet to construct Robinson a house on his York, Upper Canada farm.
    - Bill, 29 August 1798. (Page 279)
      For 6 pounds owed by Christopher Robinson to Jacob Clayton for the digging and construction of a foundation and chimneys.
    - Receipt, 9 August 1796. (Page 279)
      6p 10s 6d paid by Christopher Robinson to John Woodward and David Bennet for the construction of Christopher Robinsion's house.
    - Bill, 1793-1796. (Page 283-286)
      For money owed by Christopher Robinson to Thomas Markland for various goods purchased.
    - Bill, 1794-1795. (Page 289)
      For money owed by Christopher Robinson to Thomas Sparham, surgeon, for services rendered.
    - Bill, 1796-1797. (Page 293-296)
      For money owed by Christopher Robinson to Donald McDonell for goods purchased.
    - Bill, 1797. (Page 299)
      For money owed by William Kaiting to Christopher Robinson for legal services rendered.
    - Receipt, 16 July 1798. (Page 301)
      Christopher Robinson will pay Sincoe Ketchsin fifty dollars within six weeks.
    - Receipt. (Page 301)
      For fifty dollars paid to Sincoe Ketchsin by Christopher Robinson.
    - Receipt, 12 November 1797. (Page 301)
      Acknowledgement of three pounds owed to Abner Miles by Colonel Brackenridge, signed by Christopher Robinson.
    - Note, 2 August 1798. (Page 301)
      Christopher Robinson will leave Abner Miles with the ten dollars Robinson owes to John Woodward and David Bennet.
    - Receipt, 23 July 1798. (Page 303)
      Christopher Robinson will pay James Kemp 10p 3s 2d by 23 August 1798.
    - Christopher Robinson, York, Upper Canada, to John Robinson, Albany, 26 July 1798. (Page 303)
      Concerns an order to pay James and Nathan Ruggles 24p 5s 8d.
    - Bill, 16 June 1794. (Page 307)
      For court costs due in the case of Powley(?) v. Ashley.
    - Bill, 24 September 1794. (Page 307)
      For money owed by Ablert Ryckman to James Rivinton for law books.
    - Bill, 20 August 1794. (Page 311)
      For money owed by Christopher Robinson to Jonathan Hay, shoemaker.
    - Bill, 22 April 1796. (Page 311)
      For money owed by Christopher Robinson to Robert Maranlay for goods purchased.
    - Bill, 5 July 1796. (Page 311)
      For money owed by Christopher Robinson to James Richardson for goods and services rendered.
    - Arrest warrant, May 1797. (Page 313)
      Charging the sheriff of Kingston to find and hold James Rankin until trial in the case of a plea of debt filed by Alexander Clark. Signed by Christopher Robinson, attorney for the plaintiff.
    - Court ruling, 1797. (Page 313)
      Finding in favor of Alexander Clark in the debt case of Clark v. Rankin.
    - Bill, 1798. (Page 317)
      For money owed by Christopher Robinson for goods and services rendered by an unknown party.
    - Letter to Christopher Robinson, York, 8 April 1798. (Page 321)
      Concerns Christopher Robinson's ill health.
    - Upper Canada Gazette, 10 November 1798. (Page 323-326)
      Includes announcement of Christopher Robinson's passing on 2 November 1798.
    - Probate notice, 25 July 1798. (Page 329-330)
      Summons to Peter Robinson for payment of debts owed by the estate of Christopher Robinson.
    - Receipt, 1803 (Page 331)
      For taxes paid by the estate of Christopher Robinson.
    - Petition, 3 November 1798. (Page 333-335)
      Esther Robinson's (widow of Christopher Robinson) plea to ease the situation of her destitute family by naming Peter Robinson, eldest son, to the position of a deputy in the province of York.
    - The General Evening Post, London, 25 April 1738. (Page 339-341)
      Includes obituary of Christopher Robinson, nephew of Bishop John Robinson.
    - Letter from Bishop John Robinson, Utrecht, 2 June 1712. (Page 346)
      Concerns matters of the Queen's army.
    - Benjamin Robinson, Virginia, to Colonel Beverley Robinson, 7 August 1784. (Page 352-355)
      Concerns Beverley as benefactor of the Robinson family.
    - Frederick Robinsion, Thornbury, to John Beverley Robinson, 12 January 1816. (Page 358-361)
      Concerns business in the United Kingdom and Frederick's return to Canada.
    - William Henry Robinson, Bath, England, to John Beverley Robinson, Upper Canada, 28 April 1834. (Page 364-369)
      Letter of introduction for Admiral Vansittart's sons.
    - James Sayre, Dorchester Province, New Brunswick, to Esther Benman (sister), York, Upper Canada, 20 July 1816(?) (Page 372-375)
      Family news.
    - James Sayre, New Brunswick, to John Beverley Robinson (nephew), Toronto, Upper Canada, 25 September 1841. (Page 376-378)
      Concerns recent events in Canada and family news.
    - Letter from John Beverley Robinson, Edgewater, New Jersey, 1 April 1921. (Page 379)
      Concerns the discovery of a document about Beverley Robinson including sketch of Colonel Beverley Robinson's crest.
    - Notary public letter, 24 March 1813. (Page 380)
      Notarization of a document from Robert Lenox.